DENNIS NEVILLE EVERY

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

neville.every@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | AngelList | Medium | Portfolio

SUMMARY

I am a Full-Stack Software Engineer with 3 years of experience. I love working with React, JavaScript, and Ruby and enjoy learning new technologies. I have a passion for collaborating with others to build and architect greenfield projects, as well as upgrading and refactoring legacy code bases to improve maintainability. In my previous projects, I have often increased app performance by over 50% and reduced feature development cycles by over 67%. I'm always eager and ready for pair programming and hackathons. When I'm not coding, you can find me on the hiking or mountain biking trails.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, Hotwire, Angular, Bootstrap, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3.

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL, MySQL.

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, GitLab, AWS, Azure, Docker, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD.

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring.

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Full Stack Lead Developer

Remote

January 2022 - Present

doCasas.com - A multi-tenant SAAS application for real estate agents to manage real estate listings.

• Built with: JavaScript, Bootstrap, and Ruby on Rails.

<u>doCarros.com</u> – A multi-tenant SAAS application for vehicle dealers to manage vehicle listings.

• Built with: JavaScript, Bootstrap, and Ruby on Rails.

Spirit of Bahamas - Designed and built a website with a contact form for a real estate development project.

• Built with: JavaScript, Bootstrap, HTML, and CSS.

<u>SWEETRUSH</u>

Remote

Software Engineer IT & Security Operations

January 2023 - Present

- Develop and maintain internal applications, and upgrade legacy applications from Rails 6 to Rails 7.
- Built a web interface for the ChatGPT API with custom filters and prompts using Ruby on Rails and Hotwire.
- Reduced feature development cycles by > 67%.
- Optimized app performance > 50%.
- Increased spec coverage from 68% to 100%.
- Containerized applications with Docker.
- Replaced jQuery & CoffeeScript with Hotwire.

MICROVERSE

Remote

Mentor (Volunteer)

January 2023 - Present

- Mentored 3 junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews, resulting in 100% of them completing their milestones within the program deadlines.
- Provided advice and tips to 3 mentees on maintaining motivation, resulting in 100% of them successfully onboarding into the Microverse course curriculum.

PHILIPS

Netherlands / Brazil / Panama September 2002 – December 2014

Finance & Accounting

- Regional Controller
 - Optimized profitability by ~5% across products and regions through financial planning and analyses.
 - ~10% cost bases reduction through activity-based cost analyses and execution of cost-reduction programs.
- Audit Manager Reduced risk profile by ~5% and key risk indicators for LatAm countries through risk-based audit planning and execution for the LatAm region.

• Financial Analyst - Led cost analyses and managed the execution of cost reduction programs to increase profitability by ~3% across product groups and countries.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE October 2022 – July 2023

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously
 developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard gitflow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

ERASMUS UNIVERSITY ROTTERDAM

September 1995 - May 2002

Master of Science in Economics and Business Administration

- Experience in conducting data analysis, modeling, and decision-making by mediating between technical and business economic positions.
- Strong analytical skills combined with data processing skills.
- Knowledge of business processes and technology, with experience in developing or implementing technical solutions to improve business performance.